This is my kitchen table and also my
filing system.
Over much of the past three decades,
I've been an investor the highest
calling of mankind.
I've often thought was private equity.
And then I started interviewing.
While I watch your interviews, Coach, I
know how to do something.
I've learned in doing my interviews how
leaders make it to the top.
I asked him how much he wanted.
He said.
250.
I said, Fine.
I didn't negotiate with him.
I didn't know due diligence to have
something I'd like to sell and how they
stay there.
You don't feel inadequate now because
being only the second wealthiest man in
the world, is that right?
One of the most influential investors in
the world is Yasser Al Ramyeon.
He's the head of the Pier Fund, the
Saudi sovereign wealth fund, and also
the head of Saudi Aramco.
I had a chance to sit down with him to
talk about how he looks at the
investment world and how he looks at the
opportunities to invest in Saudi Arabia.
I was home all day yesterday preparing
for this interview.
And I was assume you were preparing for
it.
And then I watched television and I saw
President Trump and you at the tennis
matches.
So you weren't preparing for this
interview so much as I was.
Right.
It was, I think, part of the
preparation.
Okay.
So for those people that aren't familiar
with the pitch, when was the pitch
really started that the in the fun?
When it was just started.
It started when I was one year old,
1971,
and it did so many great developmental
projects in the kingdom of Saudi Arabia
when the Crown Prince became the
chairman of the Board of Beef back in
2015.
And there was a good reason for him to
say, I want to be the chairman
because he saw the potential and he saw
what a sovereign wealth fund like PIF
can do to the economy of the Kingdom of
Saudi Arabia.
What PIF have accomplished up to 2015
was good.
It wasn't great.
The strategy that we discussed at the
board level for about six months or so
was so ambitious and wanted to put PIF
and the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia on the
map of the world when it comes to
economic development and investments.
So I'll just give you an example.
Up to 2015 from 1971, our average
IRR was less than 2%.
Once we started with the new strategy
and up to date on average, we were
making about 7.2% now and the coming
two months or so
we would set the new strategy for PIF,
which is a continuation from the
original one until 2030 and from 2030
all the way to 2040 and beyond.
Okay.
So is that what the size is of the PIF
now, what the assets under management
is?
I didn't check the Wall Street today,
and I think our size is roughly it's
925, 930 at some stage.
It that was like 945.
Our target for the end of the year is
1,075,000,000,000.
Right.
So that's the biggest sovereign wealth
fund in the world.
I assume we will be the biggest
sovereign wealth fund.
Our targets by 2030 is to be at least 2
trillion.
And there's a good chance for us to be
$3 trillion.
Okay.
So no pressure on you, right?
So today, how big a team do you have to
invest this money?
You've got $945 billion under
management, so you must have a pretty
big team.
Is it a team of all Saudis?
Is the office only in Riyadh?
Where are the people and where?
How many people do you have?
Yeah.
So when
back in 2015, we had about 30 people
and it's a very small office.
Today we have our main office in Riyadh.
We have 2964 people working at the
Beehive today.
So that's a huge
growth multiple from where we were back
in 2015.
We have offices
internationally.
The first office was in New York City,
then we opened the second one in Hong
Kong, I'm sorry, London, then Hong Kong,
then Paris,
Beijing.
And we're all been in
regional offices in Cairo and Amman,
Jordan, and Manama, Bahrain,
and also in Muscat, Oman.
How about Washington, DC?
It's we're always here.
I mean, we have we we have the we have
some
some of our subsidiaries like stand up
and they have an office in San
Francisco, so they're closer to the VC
and technology kind of investment.
So when you are running a fund with $945
billion, you must be very popular,
right?
I mean, people, you must start.
Can you ever go to a restaurant?
Or a dinner or any place.
And people don't say, I've got the
greatest investment idea of all time.
That's the story of my life.
Right.
Okay.
And so how many of them turn out to be
great ideas?
I mean, we have a really good filtration
process.
We have a lot of teams that work and
different things, and we're more
proactive rather than reactive.
So in our five year strategy, usually we
put and by the way, we left our card for
our
current strategy, which started from
January 2021, and it should
take us to the end of 2025.
We put there are 13 different sectors
that we interested in, both domestically
and internationally.
So so that's the first full duration.
Then we go to the idea itself.
Does it make sense to us?
Is it a brownfield greenfield?
Is it a financial asset?
Because remember, we do too many things
and we don't look into only one kind of
assets.
We look at different asset classes.
So for people who wonder how you get to
be the head of a sovereign wealth fund
of $945 billion,
what were you doing before you had this
position?
So back in 2015, it was $150 billion.
So the amount of growth that we had was
really
unprecedented.
And it wasn't only performance, of
course, it was transfer of assets,
transfer of cash.
And also our on the performance and the
debt raising that we have.
So I used to be a CEO of an investment
bank called the Saga Forensic Capital.
So we were doing like 40% of all
investment banking activities in the
Middle East.
I started there in 2010 till 2015,
and before that I worked for the
government at the Capital Markets
Authority, which is the equivalent of
the SCC.
And before that, I, I worked as a
stockbroker in the global markets for
about eight years.
And before that, which is the very
important part of my career, was
internal audit and external audit.
So I went to I remember back
in my twenties, which was two years ago,
I started, I started and the internal
audit.
So I went from the mail room to the rest
of the barrack men to the Treasury, to
the corporate bank and to the branches
counting money, everything.
So I had a really great understanding of
how banks and operations work.
And so you're a native of Saudi Arabia?
Yes.
And you went to King Faisal University.
Okay.
And what did you study there?
I studied accounting, and then I had the
Saudi organization certified public
accountant.
When the crown prince asked you to head
up the fund.
How did you know the crown prince?
Very well before her.
Oh, no.
It was the first time I met him when I
got the call and say, okay, I got
married.
And I remember like, you know, he said,
when and it wasn't an interview,
actually.
He was like, I want you to do this one,
two or three.
And it wasn't for the sovereign wealth
funds, wasn't for before, actually, it
was for the so-called decision Support
Centre at the Royal Court.
And the idea that he had he's a great
visionary
and none of the things that we're seeing
right now in Saudi would have happened
without
a visionary and a leader like the Crown
Prince.
The way he's looking at things, it's not
based only on opinion.
He said most of the governments,
especially the Saudi government back
then, used to make their decisions based
on different advisors and based on
opinions.
What he wanted to add on top of that is
the evidence based kind of decision
making process.
So my first task was to build the
centre.
The centre now has about 350
professionals and
Social Security, politics and economy,
and it's an integral part of the
decision making process.
Within the center of government in Saudi
Arabia.
Okay.
So when you're looking at investment,
people looking in investment, is the
rate of return the most important thing
or is it whether it will help the
kingdom in some other way, or is it just
diversified out of the oil area?
What are you most focused on in terms of
looking at a good investment?
It's like a number of a number of
things.
It's a matrix.
Returns is very important,
but why are we doing certain investment
in certain sector Is there and a GDP
contribution, is there job creation?
Is there a help in our local content,
which is very important?
How can we diversify from oil?
I'll just give an example.
Back in 2015,
the Saudi GDP was about 90% based on
oil.
Today it's 53% based on non-oil GDP,
which is a great growth.
Today, the Saudi economy is about 1.1
trillion, grew from about less than 600
billion back in 2016.
This growth is coming mainly from the
non-oil GDP.
So the way we look at investments is to
take all these boxes that I mentioned
earlier and at the same time, it has to
be lucrative.
Now, all of our asset classes, like, you
know, financial assets, would be the
easiest thing to pick, right?
Going to public markets or debt capital
markets and pick these
investments will be the easiest thing.
You know, the financial returns are
coming with certain high degree of
certainty.
But what is their impact?
What is the are you an impactful
investor?
And that's part of our vision and
mission within PIF to be an impactful
investor.
And what's the definition of that?
It's to make money, of course, to help
and the prosperity and achieving the
vision 2030s
major KPIs and to develop the country.
Saudi Arabia had so many gaps and in
many things prior to 2015.
And what we wanted to do is basically
bridge these gaps.
So right now Saudi Arabia has roughly
250 billion barrels of oil reserves
proven.
Probably there's more.
So it's one of the largest is not that
close, the largest in the world.
Why not just make your economy just
complete the oil base for the next 20,
30, 40 years, not worry about the future
generations, because in our lifetimes
you have enough more oil money to just
just live off the oil money.
Why are you diversifying?
If you remember,
like if you look into history, vertigo
was at some stage one of the richest
countries in the world with all the gold
that they have from everywhere in the
world.
And that's like a disease.
And that's why the crown prince always
talk about we have the oil disease.
We cannot live only on oil because this
will make you
more dormant, less active, because you
know that there is always an oil coming
out of the ground and you you'll sell
it.
That's one.
Two, we have growth in population.
So no matter how big is your oil, you
need to find new jobs for new people.
Come in.
And today, 75% of Saudis are under the
age of 35.
You need to educate them.
You need to give them the quality of
life that they deserve and you need to
find them jobs.
So you cannot do this only with one
source of income, which is oil.
And now, of course, the gas is becoming
a big thing for us in Aramco,
but still not enough.
We need to diversify our economy.
We cannot just rely on one commodity and
say this is enough for us.
History repeats itself.
We don't want to do the same mistakes
that great nations have wouldn't do.
And so you have a certain goal that by a
certain year you want to get certain
percentage of your economy to come from
non-oil assets.
Actually, we achieved the the targets of
2030.
Now, as I said, 53% is coming non oil,
but that will never stop us because
remember, we want to grow fossil fuel
oil and gas.
And at the same time you have.
Grow the other non volume kind of GDP.
Now for most people, being the chairman
of up would be a full time job.
But you're also the chairman of Saudi
Aramco does not take a lot of time as
well.
It does.
But I'm the governor of beef.
The chairman is the crown prince.
So but as the chairman of Aramco,
it's one of
like
delights for me because it's a great
company.
It's not people when they see Aramco,
they see only oil and
maybe gas, but it's more than oil and
gas company.
The Aramco is one of the largest
investors
and technologies, and that's part of the
reason why Aramco has the lowest lift
and cost and the and the world.
And it's not because of the demography
only, but it's because of the technology
that we have.
It's it's about 90 years old.
It was
a combination of knowledge from the US
and Saudi.
We have one of the largest numbers of
these and CFOs working in Aramco.
So it's very well organized.
My role as a chairman is to do the
following.
One is the strategy
to is the monitoring of the
implementation of the strategy.
And three, to manage the board to make
sure that all board members have the
opportunity to
voice their views and at the same time
to make sure that the executive
management have all the time to explain
why they're doing the things that
they're doing or propose them.
Okay.
So for those who aren't familiar with
oil production, lifting cost is the cost
that it takes to get the oil out of the
ground barrel of oil.
And I think you're is a public
information.
What yours is is roughly five $5, 3.5,
$3.5 a barrel.
Yeah.
And if we increase our production
because Aramco today only from oil, we
have 12 million
barrels
as the maximum
sustainable capacity for our oil, we are
producing below 10 million.
So we can increase it by additional 20%
well within days.
And in order for us to do so, we have to
continuously do further exploration.
So
why our lift in cost is lower than the
others because of the use of technology.
Specially I at some stage.
Aramco had the fourth
most powerful supercomputer in the
world.
Just to put things in perspective, it
was more powerful than Nasser, so
supercomputer.
So there is a good reason for us to
invest and deploy more money and
investments in technology.
And now I we are one of the
most influential advisors to and to
improve the position of trailing get in
the oil without disrupting in the
environment and at the same time
lowering our cost.
So if you're lifting costs us three and
a half dollars a barrel
in the United States to get oil out of
the ground, probably is three or four
times as high.
So that's one of the advantage you have.
But you are not even looking for more
oil now, I guess, because you already
have 250 billion barrels of proven
reserves or you're not exploring for
more oil now because you don't need to.
Is that right?
No, not really.
We keep on.
We always looking for more.
Yeah, we always look for more.
And why are we doing it?
We find a lot of gas.
So
today, although I said that our maximum
spare capacity is about 12 million, but
if you add on top of it the gas, this
will give us about 16 million
barrels of equivalent
oil.
So with with both the gas and
and oil.
So yes, of course, we would like to
explore more and get more.
Again, to put it in perspective, our gas
today
or by 2030 will be larger than a company
like Exxon, which is like one of the
largest companies.
That's only from the gas.
If you put all the IOC is the
independent.
Oil and gas companies together.
Today they are less and production less
in revenue and less in midtown.
If we want to compete in the oil and gas
world, you're known as the chairman of
the head of Saudi Aramco.
And in the financial world, you're known
as the head of PEF.
But in the sports world, you're known as
the person who helped finance live.
What does Libby actually stand for?
Al is 50 and IV is four, which is 54.
And
I don't know how many people now
understand the Gulf terminology, but
it's 18 holes and
the perfect score, theoretically, is 54
strokes.
So that's why we said we want to get the
Gulf to the next level, which is 54
strokes.
And by the way, I have I have announced
now back when we started live golf, and
I said any one of live golf players
can achieve that.
And by the way, the lowest score
historically in golf, not only live golf
is 58.
And Bryson did it the other day with 58.
Anyone who can get to 54
strokes as a scorer
can earn a check of $54 million.
You will pay somebody who gets a 54.
So 54 score $54 million?
Yes.
Is there a big risk that's going to
happen or you think or
I hope you know, is going to be one of
my happiest days if we achieve that?
Because I will go back to my insurance
company and ask them to pay for it.
So now there's been discussion for a
while about living merging with PGA.
And you're one of the linchpins of
figuring out, is that going to you're
going to announce today what's going to
happen or
golf?
If you think about it, we have about 110
million golfers around the world.
The fan base of the sport of golf is
mainly golfers.
We have like zero zero spectators are
coming in to events or watching
broadcast for golf.
And that's one of the very few sports
and the world that has this kind of
status.
What I want is to bring golf to them non
golfers just like football, Just like
tennis, I mean, or Formula One.
How many people do you know that have
driven a Formula One car?
But but at the same time, you have
millions of people who are watching
Formula One.
I want to have the same thing for golf.
So
I'm looking forward for the day to work
with the PGA Tour, the DP World tour.
We reached out to them from day one and
fortunately things didn't go very well.
But I think hopefully in the
in the future we will be able to bring
the game of golf together.
And this will I mean, what I'm trying to
do is not to claw back from the PGA or
the DP World Tour.
What I'm trying to do is to increase the
size of the park.
So you're a golfer yourself, right?
Yes.
And you played with Tiger Woods.
You ever play with Tiger Woods?
Oh, I played almost with all the
golfers, the professional golfers from
both the PGA Tour, DP World tour, and
also on a live.
And yes, to answer your question, I
played with Tiger and his son.
Is he overrated, Tiger?
Or is he really pretty good?
I he's okay.
Yeah.
But when you're the head of live and
you've got a lot of, let's say, 25 feet
and they say, I'll give it to you or,
you know, I wish I don't do that.
So you've played with President Trump,
who's a better golfer, you or President
Trump?
That's a set secret, I think.
Okay.
All right.
So
you're also involved in what's called
football overseas here, soccer.
You're the chairman of Newcastle.
Yeah.
Now, are you bringing now in 2030 for
the World Cup will be in Saudi Arabia.
Correct.
And why is it important for you to have
the World Cup there?
It's the World Cup
and it's the, you know, the most
prestigious football event in the world.
And there are billions of people who are
watching the match.
Millions.
Millions of people who are watching the
World Cup.
It's very important to us in Saudi
because it complements the strategy that
we have when it comes to increase the
number of tourist visitors and also to
improve the quality of life for Saudis.
So we started with Newcastle United
Football Club.
It was it made perfect sense to us.
The price was
below the other of EPL teams, the
English Premier League teams, and at the
same time the potential was so high.
So we put about £350 million
and we improved everything, the
performance when we took it.
There were the relegation books and for
those of you who don't understand what's
the relegation box, it's to be relegated
to the lower league.
There were 19 out of 20 and on that
first season we went all the way up to
the seventh position and we ended up
with the season at the 11th.
The next three seasons we got the first
call up in seven years for the club.
That was last year.
We finished
in the top five and top four.
For the last two years we played the
Champions League, which is another great
event.
And
how did we do it?
We just brought in our framework and our
system to the decision making process,
and we took this experience, brought it
back to Saudi.
So we started the Saudi Professional
Football League.
And with that, as most of us know,
Cristiano Ronaldo playing there, Neymar
used to play there, Karim Benzema, which
is like the superstars of the world of
football.
And we said, okay, now we have great
players.
How we can make the clubs, great clubs.
So we're bringing in the same experience
that we have had and Newcastle United
Football Club to Saudi to Al-hilal and
to Nasser, to the two head, Al-Ahly and
the other clubs that we own indirectly
through Aramco, through Neom, through
Agadir.
So now the Saudi Football League is
ranked like the top four leagues in the
world.
Okay, so 25 years ago there weren't that
many tourists going to Saudi Arabia
other than people for the Hajj.
Yes, but today, is it tourism?
Welcome.
And you get a lot of tourists now coming
to Saudi Arabia.
Yes.
And now, I mean, the first quarter only
we had about 25 million.
Our target is to I mean, and the Vision
2030, we said we want to get 100 million
in 2030.
We achieved that last year.
This year we want to get like some
somewhere above the 100 million
tourists
threshold.
And we we are preparing ourselves to
have the right offerings, the right kind
of activities.
We start with the King Salman
International Airport, which is going to
have help us and the Expo 2030 and the
World Cup 20.
The FIFA World Cup 2034.
We want to bring in the number of
visitors to Saudi to
to numbers and the 70 million threshold.
And by 2040 should be about 120 million
passengers.
So somebody from India, they would say
come to India.
You can see the Taj Mahal.
Somebody is in China say, come and see
the Great Wall of China.
If I say I want to go to Saudi Arabia,
one of the tourist attractions I'm going
to see that's going to make me want to
go there.
So many.
And Saudi Arabia, as you know, is a big
country, different climate, different
topographies, different
offerings that are coming from
the history that we have.
Like Alula, who gives an example, is
5000 year civilization.
And we went there
but the infrastructure but some hotels
airport connect in the world too.
I know it's one of the best sites to
visit.
So you have inter alia, which is there a
historical birth place of the kingdom of
Saudi Arabia?
We have great developments over there.
And of course, you have the Red Sea
has one of the best offerings over
there.
We have Sheba.
It's like
nothing that you have seen and in your
lifetime.
The same thing is applicable to the
southern part of the country
where it's really nice green.
Even in summer, it's like in August,
temperatures there are between 18 to 25
Celsius, which is something that no one
would believe about.
So some kind of offering In Saudi, it
was often thought that if you are a
tourist in Saudi Arabia and you're a
female, it would be more complicated.
You had to wear certain things and so
forth.
The cover up.
Is that still the case?
No, no, not at all.
I mean, the tourists are welcome from
all over the world and they're all very
well respected.
So a number of years ago, the crown
prince announced a 2030 project.
What is that?
It's a vision.
And I said this many times.
Like Confucius said, there are no
favourable wins if you don't know your
destination.
This is our destination Vision 2030.
So the vision, I mean, it wasn't like
the Crown Prince
sat there for a night or so on, came and
said, This is my vision.
And it was a long process.
And in order for us to achieve this
vision, we went through so many
workshops from different parts of the
center of government and the private
sector.
We sat there for
well over one year to say, okay, here is
where we are today and here is where we
want to be, and there is a big
valley of death.
How can we go over it to go to our
vision so that that's that's the the the
vision, how to make
to get prosperity, thriving economy,
society.
And in order for us to do that, we have
to reform our
economy.
We have to reform our regulations, laws
to achieve this kind of vision.
The part that's the best known of our
vision 2030 in the United States is
probably the vision of where you're
building a modern city with, I guess, no
carbon use or very little carbon use.
A kind of modern city.
Is that one?
Will that actually open?
That's neom.
If you're referring to Neom, Neom is
a lot of people think Neom is only the
line, but that's one one of the projects
of Neom, which is
very
there's a reason why we call it not even
a mega project.
We called it a Google project.
The infrastructure in there by itself
will consume a lot of billions of
dollars.
So
and it's a new thing.
It's a new way of building
superstructures.
So it will open.
One will actually be available.
It's and it's soon it's going to it's
going to take time.
Now, what we do and we started using
technology in a better way through the
digital twin to see what's the best way
to build it, to make it livable.
The
the the communication, the technology,
the transport, everything.
So the infrastructure started a few
years ago.
We're continuing on doing that.
The other offering that we have in Neom
is OX Oxygen, which is the industrial
park.
This is ongoing.
We have so many companies from the West,
the East, from Saudi already up there,
and we have the largest green hydrogen
project in the world there to to
basically power the whole development of
neom the top of it.
We have the ski slopes, which is the
Georgina project with all the offerings
over there.
It's North and Saudi Arabia, believe it
or not, for about a month in certain
parts.
And we're looking for new technologies,
how to preserve this snow and how to
manufacture it.
So let's suppose I say I've never been
to the Middle East.
I want to go for two or three days.
I can't decide should I go to Abu Dhabi,
Dubai, Kuwait, Qatar or Saudi Arabia?
Why would I why should I go to Saudi
Arabia over the others?
What's Saudi Arabia got to attract me to
go there?
Two days.
I think you can visit a few malls in
Riyadh, and that's about it.
You need more time to explore what's
going on, and you need that like a
program, because as I said, Saudi Arabia
is a
big country.
So many different offerings.
I think what we are doing in Saudi is
complementing to whatever offerings that
you mentioned and the best to its Middle
East or the GCC should be a destination.
And this destination, like if you go to
to the Mediterranean, you go to the
Mediterranean, you don't go to only
south of France or Italy or to Greece or
to Spain.
So it's better to have more offerings.
And it's not that competition itself,
but to complement the different
offerings.
Right.
Back to the Piaf.
Historically, when people hear somebody
has a lot of money, you get a lot of
people coming to get some of that money.
I'm sure you've met every investment
professional in the western world, in
the eastern world.
Is there anybody you haven't met who
hasn't ask you for money in the last ten
or five years or so?
Less than 15 minutes, You know,
so okay, so everybody's asking for
money.
But now I thought that what you're
trying to do is not give so much money
out to people and invest the United
States as much.
But you want to have people invest back
in the kingdom.
Can you explain why you want people to
do that?
Yeah.
So as I said, historically speaking, I
used to deploy about
89% or 87, I'm sorry, 97% of our capital
within the kingdom.
Then back in 2015, we set the strategy
to diversify the economy.
We said we want to go all the way to 80%
internationally and 20% domestically.
But that doesn't mean we're selling some
of the assets in Saudi.
But all the new deployment should be
international.
Then in 2021, we said we want to
continue on the
building of the economy of Saudi Arabia.
So now we're about 80% domestic and 20%
international.
But the the percentages could be
deceiving because there was an increase
in our awam from 150 to 930, 40 billion.
So as an absolute number, we continue on
going international.
Now, the trigger for us to, especially
with the asset managers, if we want some
of them to or we want to, to play deploy
capital with some of them, we would like
them to get some of the deployment back
to the country.
Because I said, as I said before, we
need to increase and grow our local
content.
And one of the best ways to do so is to
get direct foreign investments to the
country, and especially if it's like
Co-investments with PIF,
that would add more certainty for their
future cash flows.
So people will say, okay, I'll invest in
Saudi Arabia, but what can I invest in?
Because the oil and gas world is largely
controlled by Saudi Aramco and probably
not as open to Western investors.
So what are the great opportunities for
somebody who is from the West want to
invest in the kingdom?
What areas are there that might be
available?
Almost everything.
I mean, we mentioned 13 different
sectors and you have it and the and the
cards in front of you,
all the sectors that we have, it could
be anywhere from logistics,
infrastructure,
technology.
And in technology you have friends I
champs chipsets
and renewable energy
transportation we have you know invested
in lucid and lucid now
have their own manufacturing facility
and plant in King Abdullah economic city
north of Jeddah.
We have we brought in Pirelli, Hyundai,
so many other companies to come and
invest in Saudi.
Not only that, we are doing a lot of
procurement like
everything from aeroplanes Boeing,
Airbus.
And one of the things that we ask them
to do for us if we do the procurement is
to get some of.
Or manufacture and or immoral MRO
centers.
To to the kingdom.
In this way, we are both women.
The women, by selling to us
their own products and services.
And at the same time we are women by
creating more GDP contribution and more
jobs for Saudis and than Saudis who are
residing.
The ambassador to the United States from
Saudi Arabia is here, Princess Remus
right here.
And her father also served as ambassador
many years ago.
But you're an unofficial ambassador in
many ways when you spend time here.
What is the biggest misconception that
you find Americans have about Saudi
Arabia?
That's a very interesting question.
It depends on who you're talking to.
I mean,
if you asked me the same question back
in 2015, I say almost everything.
But today, it's gradually changing.
And I'm not going to blame
the some of the Americans for their
misperception.
I will blame ourselves.
We then give our own narrative.
So we need to be more in here.
And I know Princess Reema and the
foreign affairs minister is doing great
things, but we can complement it with
the what the investment community
and the economic community and the
financial community can do to basically
give our own narrative.
I mean, we I don't want everyone to only
rely on news agencies to know what's in
Saudi.
I would like to invite everyone in here
who are interested to come and visit
Saudi.
And in fact, we can do that.
And October 27th, our next FII, the
Future Investment Initiative.
You've been there.
You've grassed us with your presence so
many times.
And the same thing to everyone in here.
Come and see what's going on.
Really only great things.
I think the transformation that we are
witnessing right now in Saudi is second
to none.
People think that what China did back in
the eighties, nineties and early 2000 is
one of the greatest transformation.
I think Saudi, what we are doing right
now could be greater.
Now you announced and the Crown Prince
announced a commitment to put, I think,
$600 billion in the United States over a
longer period of time.
This was when President Trump visited.
That's a lot of money to invest in the
United States.
I don't know how many years it is, but
what type of things are you looking for
in the United States?
And do you have a lack of people that
want to get that money from you or
what we're looking for in the United
States, is everything right?
I mean,
Saudi Arabia and the United States were
allies since the thirties with the when
the first Standard Oil company came to
Saudi and then with President Roosevelt
when he came to the Red Sea.
And they found in King Abdullah, as he's
met him.
So we've been working together since the
thirties, and I think our partnership
will continue for many, many decades to
go.
The 600 billion figure looks like a big
figure, but I think it is not because
Saudi is a big economy and the United
States of America is
the largest, the greatest economy in the
face of the earth.
So I think what we can do is just to
continue in our partnership.
We're working on the details of the 600
billion within the center of government
in Saudi and with the private sector to
see how we can achieve it.
So it's very much what since you've been
doing this, what is the investment
you've made that you're most proud of?
Is there one investment you're most
proud of?
I mean, you went into Hoover at a very
low price and some other things, but as
or one investment, you say this is the
best thing you did.
Oh, it's so many.
I mean, again, the way we we deploy
investments or capital, it's not only
for the financial returns.
One of these boxes, I think Jasmine,
which is a coffee investment, it's such
a small thing.
No one knows that the birthplace of
coffee of the world is Saudi Arabia.
It's everyone knows mocha coffee.
Mocha is a port in Yemen.
It's a port.
So they cannot grow coffee.
The coffee is was planted.
And jasmine, which is part of Saudi, and
the closest port to it is Morocco.
So everything was going to the world was
going through Saudi Arabia.
The
the Saudi coffee is one of the most
premium coffees in the world.
No one knew about this.
Not even us, the Saudis.
So we we now looking at things that we
should make us proud of, our heritage,
of our history, even if it's so small,
such so a coffee company,
camel milk, for instance.
My favorite.
Now, I didn't drink coffee.
Come on.
Milk ever in my life.
Although we have so many camels in Saudi
dates now, we were doing humane, which
is I the opposite to whatever history
that we have.
We're making new history with companies
such as Humane
Acwa Power and the renewable energy.
We want we have targets of having 50% of
our energy from renewable.
Believe it or not, in 2030, how we can
do that?
We have 70% of the renewable energy
mandate is at us.
The belief.
So so many companies.
I cannot it's like asking me who's your
favorite child?
Of course, even if you have a favorite,
you cannot get on the same.
Final question for you.
A final question.
You have been also interested in health
and longevity, and that's been something
that many people in the kingdom are
concerned about.
And you have, as I observed, lost some
weight since I saw you last.
What is the secret to losing weight
other than not eating that much?
I guess.
But but are you exercising more?
Are you taking any medications or what
is your secret to losing weight?
Actually, it's not a secret.
Not eating.
That's not eating, but intermittent
fasting.
I do.
And do you for me?
Yeah.
So I do minimum of 16 to 18 hours of
nothing.
I notice you didn't eat any lunch today
then, because it's.
Yeah, I didn't make my six.
Okay, so intermittent fasting you highly
recommend.
Oh yeah.
It's.
I mean it, it's actually it's not about
losing weight only it's good for your
body.
It's after 12 hours.
You know,
a lot of things will.
Good things will happen to your body.
It will attack the fat cells, attack all
the,
you know, potential diseases that you
will have, attack even the cancerous
cells.
So it's a really good thing.
And, you know, as part of our faith, we
do fasting for one month a year.
So I'm usually it's 12 hours.
And before I was like, yeah, that's two
too long these days.
It's like, you know, another walk in the
park for me.
So it's fine.
All right.
I'm going to try intermittent fasting
for a day and see if it works.
You.